Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES IV. Subject Files, 1928-1980
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES
  - Pike, Rev. James A.
    - 1955-66 (Box 124, Folder 36)
    - News Clippings, General 1958-64 (Box 124, Folder 37)
  - Pillsbury, Henry 1961-67 (Box 124, Folder 38)
  - Pillsbury, Mrs. Philip W. 1959-68 (Box 124, Folder 39)
  - Pincus, Gregory, M.D., 8.35, 1960-67 (Box 124, Folder 40)
  - Pl, Misc.
    - 1963-74 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - 1975-79 (Box 125)
  - "Plays for Living," Mrs. Henry N. Pratt, Chairman 1962-65 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Plimpton, Mr. and Mrs. Francis 1956-67 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Political Parties
    - Republican and Democratic National Committee Platforms 1980 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Statements Before Platform Committees, Democratic and Republican 1976 (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Statements Before Platform Committees, Democratic and Republican 1972 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Platform Planks 1964-68 (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Democratic Platform Planks 1964-69 (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Republican Platform Planks
      - 1968-74 (Box 125, Folder 9)
      - 1976 (Box 125)
  - Polls, Miscellaneous 1956-74 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Popes
    - Pope John Paul II 1979 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - Pope Paul VI
      - Encyclical-Humanae Vitae, July 29, 1968 (Box 125, Folder 12)
      - Birth Control Commission 1965-68 (Box 125, Folder 13)
  - Population, general printed material 1969-78 (Box 125, Folder 14)
  - Population Association of America, Correspondence 1959-68 (Box 125, Folder 15)
  - Population Council
    - Frederick Osborn 1955-64 (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - Dr. Nelson, Warren O., Correspondence 1955-62 (Box 125, Folder 17)
    - General Correspondence
      - 1968-71 (Box 125, Folder 18)
      - 1975-77, undated (Box 125)
      - 1961-67 (Box 125, Folder 19-20)
    - Medical Schools Program 1967-68 (Box 125, Folder 21)
    - General
      - 1970-74 (Box 125, Folder 22)
      - 1977 (Box 125)
  - Population Crisis Committee
    - Correspondence
      - 1958-74 (Box 125, Folder 23)
      - 1976-77 (Box 125)
      - 1965-68 (Box 125, Folder 24)
    - Newsletter and Misc.
      - 1965-74 (Box 125, Folder 25)
      - 1975-77 (Box 125)
  - The Population Institute 1977-79 (Box 125, Folder 26)
  - Population Reference Bureau
    - General 1963-72 (Box 125, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence 1960-70 (Box 125, Folder 28)
  - Pornography 1971 (Box 125, Folder 29)
  - Posters, Correspondence 1963-68 (Box 125, Folder 30)
  - Pr, Misc. 1963-69 (Box 125, Folder 31)
  - Projects for Population Action 1977 (Box 125, Folder 32)
  - Protestants and Other Americans United 1956-65 (Box 125, Folder 33)
  - Pu, Misc. (empty) (Box 125, Folder 34)
  - Public Affairs Activities, Permissible Limits Under Federal Law, Summary of Opinion Prepared by Pilpel and Rocket of Greenbaum, Wolff and Ernst 1979 (Box 125, Folder 35)
  - Public Affairs and Public Affairs Strategy 1977 (Box 125, Folder 36)
  - Public Affairs Institute 1955-58 (Box 125, Folder 37)
  - Public Affairs Pamphlets, Correspondence 1955-67 (Box 125, Folder 38)
  - Public Health
    - General 1955-66 (Box 125, Folder 39)
    - General Correspondence 1953-65 (Box 125, Folder 40)
  - Publications, Outside
    - Correspondence
      - 1968-74 (Box 125, Folder 41)
      - 1977 (Box 125)
      - 1967 (Box 125, Folder 42)
      - 1962-66 (Box 126, Folder 1-3)
    - Changing Times, Kiplinger Mag 1964-66 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Cosmopolitan 1956-68 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Ebony 1956-68 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Family Circle 1961-68 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Fortune Magazine 1958-67 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Good Housekeeping 1956-70 (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Harper's Magazine 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - Ladies Home Journal 1955-70 (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - Life Magazine 1957-69 (Box 126, Folder 12)
    - Look Magazine 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 13)
    - McCall's 1958-69 (Box 126, Folder 14)
    - Medical Letter 1960-66 (Box 126, Folder 15)
    - Medical Tribune 1964-69 (Box 126, Folder 16)
    - Modern Bride 1959-65 (Box 126, Folder 17)
    - The Nation 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 18)
    - Newsday 1955-67 (Box 126, Folder 19)
    - Newsweek
      - 1956-74 (Box 126, Folder 20)
      - 1979 (Box 126)
    - Pageant Magazine 1957-64 (Box 126, Folder 21)
    - Parents' Magazine 1956-74 (Box 126, Folder 22)
    - Pastoral Psychology 1957-64 (Box 126, Folder 23)
    - Reader's Digest 1955-74 (Box 126, Folder 24)
    - Redbook 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 25)
    - The Reporter 1958-67 (Box 126, Folder 26)
    - Saturday Evening Post 1955-68 (Box 126, Folder 27)
    - Saturday Review 1958-68 (Box 126, Folder 28)
    - Science 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 29)
    - Scientific American 1954-70 (Box 126, Folder 30)
    - Sexology 1956-65 (Box 126, Folder 31)
    - Time 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 32)
    - Today's Health 1955-65 (Box 126, Folder 33)
    - True Story 1955-62 (Box 126, Folder 34)
    - US News and World Report 1955-69 (Box 126, Folder 35)
    - Vision 1954-58 (Box 126, Folder 36)
    - Woman's Home Companion 1955 (Box 126, Folder 37)
  - Q, Misc. 1958-66 (Box 126, Folder 38)
  - Questionnaires
    - Cornell College Population Questionnaire 1969 (Box 126, Folder 39)
    - Government Funding 1976 (Box 126, Folder 40)
    - General, Misc. 1967-74 (Box 126, Folder 41)
  - R, Misc. 1966-68 (Box 126, Folder 42)
  - Radio, Correspondence, General
    - 1963-74 (Box 126, Folder 43)
    - 1975-78 (Box 126)
  - Rainwater, Dr. Lee 1958-66 (Box 126, Folder 44)
  - Randolph, A. Philip, Educational Fund 1966-69 (Box 126, Folder 45)
  - Re, Misc. 1955-69 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights 1978-79 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Research Institute of America 1963-67 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Right to Life Groups
    - 1975-78 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - 1972-74 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Project Proposal to Investigate, Draft and Comments 1975 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - The Eleanor Roosevelt Institute, Statement by Hon. Justine Wise Polier 1980 (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Salvation Army, Correspondence 1959-66 (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Se, Misc. 1960-66 (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Searle and Co., G.D.
    - Conference, Family Planning Clinics 1965-66 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence
      - 1966-74 (Box 127, Folder 11)
      - 1977-78 (Box 127)
      - 1956-65 (Box 127, Folder 12-13)
    - Thrombophlebitis Conference 1962 (Box 127, Folder 14)
  - Selinger, Mrs. Maurice A. 1956-68 (Box 127, Folder 15)
  - Senior, Clarence 1955-68 (Box 127, Folder 16)
  - Sh, Misc. 1962-68 (Box 127, Folder 17)
  - Shi, Misc. 1963-66 (Box 127, Folder 18)
  - Shockley, William, General Correspondence 1963-66 (Box 127, Folder 19)
  - Si, Misc.
    - 1964-74 (Box 127, Folder 20)
    - 1978-79 (Box 127)
  - Siecus 1970-73 (Box 127, Folder 21)
  - Sk, Misc.
    - 1961-74 (Box 127, Folder 22)
    - 1979 (Box 127)
  - Calderone, Dr. Mary S. Siecus, Correspondence 1964-69 (Box 127, Folder 23)
  - Sloane-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research 1957-65 (Box 127, Folder 24)
  - Sm, Misc. 1961-68 (Box 127, Folder 25)
  - Smith, Kline and French Labs 1957-66 (Box 127, Folder 26)
  - Social Work, Job Applications 1961-66 (Box 127, Folder 27)
  - Social Workers' Pamphlet 1962-63 (Box 127, Folder 28)
  - Society for Ethical Culture, Correspondence 1962-63 (Box 127, Folder 29)
  - Society for International Development
    - Correspondence 1962-68 (Box 127, Folder 30)
    - General 1959-68 (Box 127, Folder 31)
  - Southeimer, Morton 1955-65 (Box 127, Folder 32)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, Correspondence 1963-66 (Box 127, Folder 33)
  - Sn, Misc. 1959-69 (Box 127, Folder 34)
  - Sp, Misc. 1962-70 (Box 127, Folder 35)
  - Speeches, Misc.
    - 1954-74 (Box 127, Folder 36)
    - 1978 (Box 127)
  - Sponsorship
    - Honorary Sponsors Council 1964-73 (Box 127, Folder 37)
    - Events, Groups, Organizations, Misc.
      - 1969-74 (Box 127, Folder 38)
      - 1976 (Box 127)
    - Hammond Museum 1971 (Box 127, Folder 39)
  - St, Misc. 1958-69 (Box 127, Folder 40)
  - Stern, Mrs. Julius Long, Correspondence 1956-64 (Box 127, Folder 41)
  - Sti, Misc.
    - 1964-74 (Box 127, Folder 42)
    - 1975-78 (Box 127)
  - Stone, Dr. Abraham
    - Correspondence 1951-56 (Box 127, Folder 43)
    - Obituary Correspondence 1959-60, [no folder 45] (Box 127, Folder 44)
    - Obituary Clippings, Publicity 1959 (Box 127, Folder 46)
  - Stone, Hannah, M.D. 1937-41 (Box 127, Folder 47)
  - Straus, Donald 1960-69 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee 1964 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Stycos, J. Mayone 1960-64 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Su, Misc.
    - 1962-74 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - 1977-79 (Box 128)
  - Sulloway, Alvah W. 1958-60 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Survey of Laws: Birth Control and Family Planning in U.S. 1968-70 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Syntex
    - 1964-74 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - 1975-79 (Box 128)
  - Symposium, Authors', Population Problems 1961 (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - Sweezy, Alan, Correspondence 1970-71 (Box 128, Folder 9)
  - T, Misc. 1962-68 (Box 128, Folder 10)
  - Tax Exemption
    - Internal Revenue Service, 501(c)(3) and (4), Publicly Supported 170(b)(1)(A)(v) 1979-80 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Internal Revenue Service 501(c)(3) and (4) 107(b)(1) (v1), "Public Supported"
      - 1938-74 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - 1975-78 (Box 128)
    - IRS 501 (c) 3, Lobbying Provisions 1977-78 (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - Record Keeping for Affiliates Electing to Lobby 1978 (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Public Affairs Activities, Relevant Provisions of Law, Harriet F. Pilpel and Laurie Rockett 1979 (Box 128, Folder 15)
    - Summary of Opinion on Public Affairs Activities, (Permissible Limits Under Federal Law), Prepared by Pilpel and Rockett of Greenbaum, Wolff and Ernst 1979 (Box 128, Folder 16)
    - Federal 1960 (Box 128, Folder 17)
  - 1976 Tax Reform Act 1976-77 (Box 128, Folder 18-19)
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969
    - General Explanation of the Tax Reform Act of 1969, Excerpts, 1970 (Box 128, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and General
      - 1969-74 (Box 128, Folder 21)
      - 1975-80 (Box 128)
  - TV
    - American B'casting Co., Correspondence 1963-69 (Box 128, Folder 22)
    - Columbia B'casting Co.
      - Correspondence 1963-69 (Box 128, Folder 23)
      - General 1959-72 (Box 128, Folder 24)
    - Nat'l B'casting Co.
      - Correspondence 1964-72 (Box 128, Folder 25)
      - Misc. Announcements, Etc. (Box 128)
        - 1956-74 (Box 128, Folder 26)
        - 1980-81 (Box 128)
    - General Correspondence
      - 1964-74 (Box 128, Folder 27)
      - 1975 (Box 128)
  - Testimonies (Box 128)
    - 1976-80 (Box 128, Folder 28-29)
    - 1975 (Box 128, Folder 30)
    - 1964-74 (Box 128, Folder 31-34)
    - Criteria and Circumstances for PPWP to Testify 1971 (Box 128, Folder 35)
  - Th, Misc. 1964-69 (Box 128, Folder 36)
  - Tietze, Dr. Christopher
    - 1953-74 (Box 128, Folder 37)
    - Publications 1961-63 (Box 128, Folder 38)
  - Time Capsules 1974 (Box 128, Folder 39)
  - To, Misc. 1959 (Box 128, Folder 40)
  - Tr, Misc. 1963-72 (Box 128, Folder 41)
  - United Community Funds and Councils of America 1956-70 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - United Nations Association of the United States
    - 1969-74 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - 1975 (Box 129)
  - U.S. Association for the Club of Rome 1977 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Government, General Correspondence 1955-70 (Box 129, Folder 4-5)
  - U.S. Government
    - Anti-Poverty Program
      - Correspondence 1964-69 (Box 129, Folder 6-7)
      - Rural Family Planning Programs
        - Edited by Frederick S. Jaffe, May 1967 (Box 129, Folder 8)
        - An Approach to Programming of Services by Frederick S. Jaffe 1967 (Box 129, Folder 9)
      - Misc. Printed Material 1964-68 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Chamber of Commerce 1955-69 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission 1978 (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights 1974 (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - Release from Dept. HEW, Katherine Oettinger, Appt., (Bio) 1967 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Government, Dept. Health, Ed. and Welfare
      - Correspondence
        - Secretary Joseph A. Califano 1977-78 (Box 129, Folder 15)
        - 1966-74 (Box 129, Folder 16)
        - 1975-77 (Box 129)
      - General
        - 1961-74 (Box 129, Folder 17)
        - 1976-78 (Box 129)
      - Correspondence 1961-66 (Box 129, Folder 18)
      - American Indian Public Health 1955-69 (Box 129, Folder 19-21)
      - Bureau Community Health Services, Bureau Common Reporting Requirement, BCRR 1976-77 (Box 129, Folder 22)
      - BCHS Draft of Meeting with Dr. Martin, Director of BCHS 1977 (Box 129, Folder 23)
      - Bureau of Community Health Services, General Correspondence 1977-78 (Box 129, Folder 24)
      - Children's Bureau
        - Booklets, Printed Matter 1960-68 (Box 129, Folder 25)
        - Correspondence 1966-72 (Box 129, Folder 26-27)
        - General 1955-65 (Box 129, Folder 28)
        - Div. of Grant Adm. Policy, Children's Bureau, Correspondence 1968-70 (Box 129, Folder 29)
        - Mic. Project, Children's Bureau, Correspondence 1967-69 (Box 129, Folder 30)
      - BCHS/HSA, List of Family Planning Grantees by Region 1976 (Box 130, Folder 1)
      - Family Planning Services and Population Research Act 1970-73 (Box 130, Folder 2)
      - Family Planning Services 1976 Revisions of 5 Year Plan (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Federal Regulations 1977 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Food and Drug Administration
      - 1969-74 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - 1977-78 (Box 130)
      - 1957-68 (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - Report on the Oral Contraceptive 1966 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - General Counsel 1979 (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Government Reporting Requirements 1976 (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Guidelines for Family Planning Services 1975 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Health Resources Administration, Nat'l Guidelines, Health Planning 1978 (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Health Services and Mental Health Administration (HSMHA)
      - 1973-74 (Box 130, Folder 12)
      - 1975-77 (Box 130)
    - HEW Disaster Hospital, Program Phaseout, Correspondence 1973 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Migrant Health Section 1960-64 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - Nat'l Center Family Planning Services
      - 1970-74 (Box 130, Folder 15)
      - 1975 (Box 130)
    - Nat'l Center for Health Statistics
      - 1970-71 (Box 130, Folder 16)
      - Workshops 1970-71 (Box 130, Folder 17)
    - Nat'l Institutes Health, Recombinant DNA Research 1977 (Box 130, Folder 18)
    - Nat'l Institute of Health
      - 1956-71 (Box 130, Folder 19-21)
      - Reports, General 1961-71 (Box 130, Folder 22)
    - Nat'l Reporting System for Family Planning Service (NRSFPS)
      - 1972-74 (Box 130, Folder 23)
      - 1975-78 (Box 130)
    - Nat'l Institute Health, Social Research, Dr. E. Albritton 1950-62 (Box 130, Folder 24)
    - Office of Adolescent Pregnancy Programs 1979 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    - PSROS (Professional Standard Review Organizations) 1974 (Box 130, Folder 26)
    - Program Management Reporting Requirements 1976 (Box 130, Folder 27)
    - Public Health Service
      - Center for Disease Control 1977-78 (Box 130, Folder 28)
      - General, Correspondence (Box 130)
        - 1956-74 (Box 130, Folder 29)
        - 1975-77 (Box 130)
      - 1942 and 1953 Policies, General, 1942-67 (Box 130, Folder 30)
    - Regional Conferences
      - 1966-72 (Box 130, Folder 31)
      - General, Misc. 1966 (Box 130, Folder 32)
    - Report from the Chair of the Task Group on PGM, "Alternatives - Abortion," 1977 (Box 130, Folder 33)
    - Report of the President's Biomedical Research Panel 1976 (Box 130, Folder 34)
    - Secretary's Commission on Medical Malpractice 1971-72 (Box 130, Folder 35)
    - Social and Rehabilitation Service 1973-74 (Box 130, Folder 36)
    - Title XX, Social and Rehabilitation Services 1975 (Box 130, Folder 37)
  - United World Federalist 1969 (Box 130, Folder 38)
  - Vista, Workshop, "Volunteers in Service to America," 1965-74 (Box 130, Folder 39)
  - Vogt, Dr. William 1961-68 (Box 130, Folder 40)
  - Whelpton, Pascal K., Deceased April 6, 1964, 1962-64 (Box 130, Folder 41)
  - Workum, Mrs. Fiefield, printed material 1955-79 (Box 130, Folder 42)
  - World Health Organization
    - Nat'l Citizens Committee, Correspondence 1964-71 (Box 130, Folder 43)
    - 22nd World Health Assembly, Correspondence 1969 (Box 130, Folder 44)
    - General 1954-69 (Box 130, Folder 45)
    - 22nd World Health Assembly, General, circa 1969 (Box 130, Folder 46)
  - World Mental Health Assembly 1969 (Box 130, Folder 47)
  - World Neighbors 1961-69 (Box 130, Folder 48)
  - YWCA
    - National Convention 1958-73 (Box 130, Folder 49)
    - General 1955-68 (Box 130, Folder 50)
  - Zero Population Growth
    - 1969-74 (Box 130, Folder 51)
    - 1975-77 (Box 130)